《谍影重重2》
士兵 这次不是训练
This is not a drill, soldier.
清楚吗？
We clear on that?
这次可是来真的 行动吧
This is a live project. you're a go.
行动吧
You're a go.
训练结束 训练结束
Training is over. Training is over.
（印度 果阿）
我没事 没事
I'm okay. It's fine.
只是有点头疼
Just a headache.
你的额头很烫
You're burning up.
没关系
It's okay.
头疼而已
Just a headache.
- 想起什么新的事情了么？- 没有
- Anything new? - No.
只有一些破碎的片断
It's just bits and pieces.
我能听到康克林的声音
I can hear Conklin's voice,
还有那张相片 可是…
and there's that photograph, but…
我坚持不下去
I just can't stay with it.
- 也许只是场噩梦而已 - 它发生过
- But you're sure it's not just a bad dream? - It happened.
是一次任务
It was a mission.
我在那儿
And I was there.
你应该把它写下来
You should write it down.
- 两年了 我们一直在这个本子上记录着 - 还不到两年
- Two years we're scribbling in that notebook… - It hasn't been two years.
可是没有任何好转 翻来覆去都是同样的画面
It's always bad, and now it's just the same thing over and over again.
所以我们才要把它记下来啊 因为你早晚会想起一些好的事情的
But that's Why we write it down. Because sooner or later, you remember something good.
我的确记得一些好的事情
I do remember something good.
一直记得
All the time.
（德国 柏林）
- 最后一次检查 - 全体注意
- I want one final go around. - All teams listen up.
- 准备做最后一次检查 - 二队 看到目标立刻向我报告
- We are standing by fiorfinal green. - Survey Two, I need to know when you've got eyes.
- 这是二队 我看到了 - 收到
- This is Survey Two. I have eyes. - Copy that.
一队 这里是总部 你们看到目标了么？
Survey One, this is Hub. Do you have visual contact?
总部 这里是一队 一号目标正在移动
Hub, this is Survey One. Mobile One is in motion.
三队 很好
Survey Three, that is good.
- 总部 - 马歇尔局长 从兰利打来的
- Hub. - Director Marshal from Langley.
- 兰利 - 请等一下
- Langley. - Stand by, please.
- 马丁？- 是我 还有唐尼和杰克·韦勒
- Martin? - I'm here. So is Donnie and Jack Weller.
我们听说你把全部的拨款都用上了
We understand you're using the full allocation for this buy.
- 这才是刚刚开始 - 这可是一大笔钱啊 帕姆
- It's where we came out. - It's a lot of money, Pam.
对于一个小偷 一个间谍来说是一大笔钱
For a thief, a mole.
可是如果真能找出疑犯的名单 这值十倍的价钱
If it does nothing more than narrow the list of suspects, it's a bargain at 10 times the price.
总部 这里是二队 护送离开了
Hub, this is Survey Two. Escort is breaking off…
一号目标进入大楼
Mobile One is entering the building.
先生们 交易就要开始了 恕我直言 没有什么好讨论的了
Gentlemen, I have the seller on-site and in play. Quite frankly, there's nothing much more to discuss.
- 好吧 帕姆 交给你了 - 行动
- All right, Pam. your call. - Go.
- 我们开始了 - 仅用语音联络
- We're on. - Audio contact only.
现在切到一号频道
Switching to channel one now.
收到
Copy that. It's affirmative.
- 东西带来了么？- 带来了 跟我来
总部 一号目标和卖家已经进入办公室
Hub, Mobile One and seller have entered the office.
收到
Copy that.
都在这儿了么？
This is everything?
都在这儿了 这些文件能证明谁偷了你们的钱
是枪声
Those were shots.
一队 请回话 一队 发生了什么事？你们看到什么了？
Survey One, come in. Survey One, I need to know what happened. What do you see?
- 看到有影子么？我什么都没看到 - 你们看到什么了？
- Do you see any shadows? I see nothing. - What is yourvisual?
- 派人过去 快！- 快去 库尔特
- Get some men in there. Get some men in there right now. - Pull it up, Kurt.
有没有看到任何动静？一号 请回话！
Eye contact. I don't care If it's visual… Mobile One, can you copy, please?
- 收到吗？一号？- 对不起
- Are you there, Mobile One? - I'm sorry.
你看到什么了？
What do you see?
…在柏林举行的石油协会年度会议…
…Petroleum Association's annual conference here in Berlin…
这是佩克斯石油公司的首席执行官尤里·格列特科夫
is Pekos Oil chief executive officer Yuri Gretkov.
在短短6年时间内 格列特科夫把佩克斯变成了一个石油帝国 因而…
In just six years, Gretkovhas turned Pekos into an oil empire, which in turn…
他也成为俄国最富有的人之一…
He's become one of the wealthiest men in Russia…
在巩固了里海石油开采权并控制了…
after consolidating drilling rights in the Caspian Sea and gaining control of one ofthe wo…
你迟到了
文件
任务完成以后再给你剩下的钱
我得洗个澡
抓紧时间 飞机一小时后起飞
情报准确吗？
他会在那儿的
多少钱？
How much?
- 早上好 先生 - 早上好
- Good morning, sir. - Morning.
他是我的朋友 他家里有亲戚去世了
He is my friend. There's been a death in the family.
不知道你有没有见过他
I wonder If you've seen him.
- 嗨 - 上车
- Hey. - Get in.
- 怎么了？- 我们暴露了
- What's wrong? - We're blown.
- 怎么会？- 我们在一个地方呆得太久了
- How? - We pushed it. We got lazy.
你疯啦！
Idiot!
这是我第二次见到这个家伙了
All right. That's twice now I've seen the same guy.
我在城里见过他 在电报局里
I saw him in town. He was at the telegraph office.
- 你确定吗？你怎么能确定呢？- 肯定有问题
- Are you sure? How-How can you be sure? - It's just wrong.
那个家伙 他开的车 他穿的衣服 肯定有问题
The guy, the car he's driving, what he's wearing… it's just wrong.
- 杰森 听着 冷静一点 可能是别人 - 这是真的
- Look, Jason, let's stay calm. It could be anybody. - This is real.
这是真的 是他 他就在那儿
This is real. That's him. That's him right there.
把头低下 银色现代车 低下头
Get your head down. Silver Hyundai. Get your head down.
他有多远？
How far is he?
多远？
How far?
100米
A hundred meters.
来 握着方向盘 你来开
Here, take the wheel. you're gonna drive.
交换
Switch.
一直往大桥那里开
Just head to the bridge.
- 这里转弯 从田里穿过去 - 坐稳了
- Turn here. Cut through the field. - Hang on.
好了 你继续往家里开 我一小时后去和你碰头
All right, you keep going to the shack. I'll meet you there in one hour.
我在桥的那一头下车 他只可能走这条路才能跟上咱们
I'm gonna bail out on the other side of this bridge. It's the only way he can follow us.
- 如果他不是你认为的人呢？- 就是他们 是「踩石」
- What If it's not who you think it is? - It's them. It's Treadstone.
- 杰森 不要这么做 - 玛丽 我警告过他们
- Jason, don't do it. - Look, Marie, I warned 'em.
- 我不希望你这么做 - 我告诉过他们 如果不放过我们会有什么后果
- I don't want you to do it. - I told them what would happen If they didn't leave us alone.
- 这样永远都不会结束 我不希望… - 我们没得选择
- It's never gonna be over like this. I don't want… - We don't have a choice.
你有选择的
Yes, you do.
谢谢你
Thank you.
电源线上放置了两个炸弹 其中一个失效了
Two of these explosive charges placed on the power lines, and one of them failed.
这是没有爆炸的那个上面留下的指纹
The fingerprints from the one that didn't go off.
- 找不到和指纹相符的德国人？- 是的 没有
- And the Germans can't match it? - No. Nobody's got it.
所有能查的数据库都查过了 只有兰利的数据库进不去
We checked out every database we could access. But we're hooked into Langley now.
- 运行一下 - 好的
- Run it. - Okay.
「踩石」是什么？
What the hell's Treadstone?
好了 准备飞机 我们去兰利
All right. Get me a flight. We're going to Langley.
（谢列梅捷沃国际机场 俄罗斯 莫斯科）
伯恩呢？
搞定了
你确定他死了？
我们已经没有余地…
一切都结束了 伯恩 文件 指纹
我一个月后再和你联系
死了两个人 三百万现金没了 奈斯基的文件也没拿到
Two men dead, three million in cash gone, no Neski files,
还搞得人人皆知
and all very public.
我们还算是一个秘密机构吗？
This is still a clandestine agency, no?
我认为这次事件并不是一次失败
I don't view this event as a failure.
- 难道这叫成功？- 我们有了一条线索
- you call it a success? - We have a lead.
杀手留下了一个指纹 他是我们的人
A fingerprint left by the assassin. He's one of us.
- 是谁？- 关于「踩石」 你能告诉我多少？
- Who is it? - What can you tell me about Treadstone?
- 「踩石」？- 线索正是在此中断的
- "Treadstone?" - It's where the trail dead-ends.
如果你想要答案 就必须给我…
If you want an answer, you're going to have to give me…
五级S.C.I.权限
a level-five S.C.I. access.
我们真的有线索 马蒂
We have a lead, Marty.
好吧 你获准了
All right. you've got your clearance.
但你将受到严格的监控
But you're on a very short leash.
你要向我们提供完整的报告 我要了解你们的进展
And you'll give a full report to the group. I wanna know where you're going with this.
是
Sir.
（意大利 那不勒斯）
沃德？
Ward?
- 谁？- 帕梅拉·兰蒂
- Yes? - Pamela Landy.
嗨 帕姆 有什么可以帮忙的？
Hey, Pam. What can I do for you?
- 我希望你有时间和我见一面 - 什么事？
- I was hoping you had some time for me. - Time for what?
- 实际上 我现在就有空 - 听起来不像是好事嘛 让我查一下日程安排
- I'm free right now, actually. - That sounds ominous. Let me check my schedule.
- 抱歉 我要 呃… - 有什么需要帮忙的？
- Excuse me. I need to, uh… - Excuse me. Can I help you?
- 是的 我是来见艾博特先生的 - 二十分钟？
- Yeah, I'm here to see Mr.Abbott. - Twenty minutes?
到时见
See ya.
- 「踩石」行动 - 我从来没听说过
- Operation Treadstone. - Never heard of it.
- 它总不会凭空消失吧 - 恕我冒昧 帕姆 我认为你也许无权过问这些事情
- That's not gonna fly. - With all due respect, Pam, I think you might've wandered past your pay grade.
我有马歇尔局长的授权 可以不受限制地…
That's a warrant from Director Marshall granting me unrestricted access to…
调查与「踩石」有关的所有人员和材料
all personnel and materials associated with Treadstone.
- 那么 你想知道什么？- 我想了解它
- So, what are we looking at? - I wanna know about it.
了解它？这是一个杀手小队 以黑对黑
Know about it? It was a kill squad. Black-on-black.
我们两年前把它解散了 这里没人想要了解「踩石」
We closed it down two years ago. Nobody wants to know about Treadstone. Not around here.
所以我认为你最好把这个带回去给马蒂 让他知道你究竟在做什么
So I think you better take this back to Martyand let him know exactly what you're doing.
他知道 我去查过档案了 我手里有文件 沃德
He does. I've been down to the archives. I have the files, Ward.
- 我们来谈谈康克林吧 - 你到底想查什么 帕姆？
- Let's talk about Conklin. - What are you after, Pam?
你想炒了我吗？你想坐我的位子 是吗？
You wanna fry me? You want my desk. Is that it?
- 我想知道发生了什么 - 发生了什么？
- I wanna know what happened. - What happened?
杰森·伯恩 既然你手里有文件 我们就废话少说吧
Jason Bourne happened. you got the files. Then let's cut the crap.
康克林对他的手下要求非常严酷 所以这帮人几乎要崩溃了
Conklin had these guys woundso tight, they were bound to snap.
伯恩是他手下的头号杀手 有一次他接了个任务 搞砸了 再也没有回来
Bourne was his number-one. The guy went for ajob, screwed the op, never came back.
康克林没有办法 找不到伯恩 没法调整 事情越来越糟
Conklin couldn 't fix it, couldn 't find Bourne, couldn 't adjust. It all went sideways.
所以你就杀了康克林？我的意思是 既然要废话少说
So you had Conklin killed? I mean, If we're cutting the crap.
我在这里呆了30年 结了两次婚
I 've given 30 years and two marriages to this agency.
我在四块大陆上工作过 明年我就要退休了
I've shoveled shit on four continents. I'm due to retire next year.
但是如果你认为我会坐在这里让你这么摆弄
But If you think I'm gonna sit here and let you dangle me with this,
那你就见鬼去吧…还有马歇尔
you can go to hell… and Marshall too.
我只能这么做
It had to be done.
- 伯恩呢？他现在在哪儿？- 死在哪个臭水沟里了
- And Bourne? Where is he now? - Deadin a ditch.
- 或者在摩加迪沙的哪个酒吧里喝醉了 谁知道 - 我想我知道
- Drunk in a barin Mogadishu. Who knows? - I think I do.
上周我在柏林的一笔生意砸了
I had a deal going down in Berlin last week.
交易进行当中 我的人和卖家都被杀死了
During the buy, both our case officer and the seller were killed.
杀手就是杰森·伯恩
They were killed by Jason Bourne.
他们在等你上去
They're ready for us upstairs.
（中情局分局 英国 伦敦）
7年前 中情局有一笔两千万美元的资金 在经过莫斯科电汇的过程中不翼而飞了
Seven years ago, $20 million of C.I.A. funds disappeared during a wire transfer through Moscow.
在随后的调查中 一位名为弗拉迪米尔·奈斯基的俄国政客与我们联系
In the investigation that followed, wewere contacted by a Russian politician, Vladimir Neski.
奈斯基称有人泄密 我们的钱被内部的人吞掉了
Neski claimed we had a leak and that we'd been ripped off by one of our own.
- 是这样吗？- 至今仍不知道
- And were we? - We never found out.
正当我们想约奈斯基先生会面时 他却被杀了
We were negotiating a meet with Mr. Neski when he was killed.
- 谁干的？- 他的妻子
- By who? - His wife.
这件案子就这么一直搁着 直到上个月我们找到一个线人
The case had gone cold until a month ago when we found a source.
另一个在柏林的俄国人声称 他有关于奈斯基被谋杀的证据
Another Russian in Berlin who claimed to have access to the Neski murder files.
我们本以为又有希望了
We thought we had another bite at the apple.
结果他却被我们自己的杀手杰森·伯恩杀死了
Turns out the assassin was one of our own…Jason Bourne.
我知道「踩石」在这里不是个受欢迎的论题
I know Treadstone's not a very popular subject around here,
但是随着调查的深入 我们发现了一些有趣的事情
but we found some interesting things when we dug a little deeper.
这是康克林的个人电脑
This is Conklin's personal computer.
他的「踩石」文件堆里塞满了 他既不需要也无权看到的解码密钥和案件档案
His Treadstone files are bloated with code keys and case files that he neither needed nor had clearance for.
在硬盘里我们找到一个被删除的文件 其中有苏黎世银行的一个账号
Buried in the hard drive, we found a deleted file with an account number to a bank in Zurich.
在他死的时候 他的个人账户里有76万美金
At the time ofihis death, he was sitting on a personal account in the amount of $760, 000.
你知道他的经费预算吗？为了让他将事情保密 我们一直在砸钱给他
You know what his budget was? We were throwing money at him and asking him to keep it dark.
- 这是他自己的账户 他肯定干了些什么 - 你肯定这些情报确切么？
- It was his own account. He was up to something. - This is supposed to be definitive?
- 我已经有两个人死在柏林了 这是肯定的 - 那你的结论是？
- What's definitive is that I just lost two people in Berlin. - So what's your theory?
康克林从坟墓里爬出来维护自己的名声？这个人已经死了
Conklin's reaching out from the grave to protect his good name? The man is dead.
- 没有人对此持有异议 沃德 - 帮帮忙 马蒂 你了解康克林的
- No one's disputing that, Ward. - For Christ's sake, Marty, you knew Conklin.
这符合情理吗？根本不可能！
Does this scan? I mean, at all?
直接说重点 帕姆
Cut to the chase, Pam.
我认为伯恩和康克林是一伙儿的
I think that Bourne and Conklin were in business together,
既然事情牵涉到伯恩 那么不管我在柏林想买的是什么情报
that Bourne's still involved and that whatever information I was trying to buy in Berlin…
都值得他重新现身杀人灭口
was big enough to bring Bourne out from hiding to kill again.
这符合情理吗？
How's that scan?
请原谅 先生 您可能不相信
Excuse me, sir, but you're not gonna believe this.
杰森·伯恩的护照刚刚在那不勒斯出现
Jason Bourne's passport just popped up on the grid in Naples.
好的 接那不勒斯 他们得知道要对付的是什么人
Okay. Contact Naples. They need to know who they're dealing with.
找到我们在当地的人
Find out what kind of local assets we have in place there.
不 没事 有个家伙的名字出现在电脑上而已
Nah, it's nothing. Some guy's name came up on the computer.
是的 嗨 听着 汤姆 我过会儿给你打回去 好吗？
Yeah. Hey, listen, Tom, I'm gonna call you back, okay?
好的
All right.
伯恩先生 我是约翰·内文斯 美国领事馆的
Mr. Bourne, I'm John Nevins. I'm with the U.S. Consulate.
我想问你几个问题
I just have a few questions for you.
你从丹吉尔来 是么？
You're coming out of Tangier. Is that correct?
你来那不勒斯的目的是什么？
What's the, uh, nature of yourvisit to Naples?
我不知道你干了什么 我也不知道你为谁工作
Look, I don't know what you did, and I don't know who you're working for.
但是我向你保证…
But I promise you this…
你在这儿就得遵守这边的规矩
you're gonna play ball one way or the other.
我是内文斯
This is Nevins.
我是汤姆·克罗宁 中情局行动长官 从弗吉尼亚州兰利市打来的
This is Tom Cronin, C.I. Operations Officer calling from Langley, Virginia.
- 你是不是拘留了一个叫做杰森·伯恩的人？- 是的
- Do you have a Jason Bourne in custody? - Yes, I do.
听着 他是我们通缉的要犯
Listen, he's an agency priority target.
- 安置好他以后立刻给我打电话 - 是
- Call me back as soon as he's secure. - I understand.
他被拘留了 这是号码
He's been detained. Here's the number.
领事馆的一名军官正在审问他
He's being interrogated by a field officer out of the consulate.
- 喂 - 我是帕梅拉·兰蒂 中情局主管
- Hello. - This is Pamela Landy, C.I. supervisor.
情况怎么样？
Where do we stand?
我 呃 我想他跑了
I, uh, think he got away.
妈的
Damn it.
- 有没有封锁该地区？- 封锁？没 没有
- Have you locked down the area? - Locked it down? No. No.
这里是 呃…这里是意大利 我们一般不封锁…
This is, uh… This is Italy. They don't exactly lock down…
- 你为机构工作了几年了？- 我？四年
- How long have you worked for the agency? - Me? For four years.
如果你还想干第五年的话 就给我好好听着 伯恩身上有武器 极度危险
If you ever wanna make it to five, you're gonna listen to me real close. Bourne is armed and extremely dangerous.
上周他在柏林暗杀了两个人 其中一个是一名资深军官
Last week in Berlin he assassinated two men… one a highly experienced field officer.
我要你确保该地区的安全 保护好所有的证据 立刻执行
I want you to secure that area. I want any evidence secured, and I want it done right now.
- 听懂了吗？- 是的 先生…不 女士
- Is that clear? - Yes, sir… ma'am.
我45分钟后乘飞机去柏林 也就是说你要在30分钟内给我回话
I'm getting on a plane to Berlin in 45 minutes, which means you're gonna call me back in 30.
当我问起你情况如何的时候 你最好能给我个满意的答复
And when I ask you where we stand, I had better be impressed.
- 柏林？- 我已经在那里准备了一队人
- Berlin? - I already have a team in place there.
我怀疑伯恩准备在那不勒斯成家
I doubt that Bourne's in Naples readyto start a family.
- 你根本不知道面对的是什么 - 你知道么？
- you have no idea what you're getting into. - Do you have any idea?
从他离开「踩石」的那刻起 他杀掉和躲避了你派去寻找他的每一个人
From the minute he left Treadstone, he's killed and eluded every single person that you've sent to find him.
- 你以为自己读了几份关于杰森·伯恩的文件 就变成专家了吗？- 这是我的案子 沃德
- you read a couple of files on Jason Bourne, and that makes you an expert? - This is my case, Ward.
够了 我要你们一起上飞机
Enough. I want you both on that plane.
我们 所有的人 都要把这件以前懒得做的 或者没能力做的事情解决掉
We are, all of us, going to do what we were either too lazy or inept to do the last time around.
我们要找到这个杂种 把他干掉
We're gonna find this son of a bitch and take him down.
我不会让杰森·伯恩继续嚣张下去了
I 'm not having Jason Bourne destroy any more of this agency.
- 你们两个明白了吗？- 是
- Is that definitive enough for you? - Yes.
杰森·伯恩带有武器 极度危险
Jason Bourne is armedand extremely dangerous.
上周他在柏林暗杀了两个人 其中一个是一名资深军官
Last week in Berlin he assassinated two men… one a highly experienced field officer.
我要你…
I want that area…
…他暗杀了两个人… 一个是一名资深军官
…he assassinated two men… one a highly experienced field officer.
我要你确保该地区的安全 保护好所有的证据 立刻执行…
I want that area secured. I want any evidence secured, and I want it done right now…
士兵 这次不是训练
This is not a drill, soldier.
士兵 这次不是训练 士兵 这次不是训练
This is not a drill, soldier. This is not a drill, soldier.
清楚吗？清楚吗？
We clear on that? We clear on that?
（荷兰 阿姆斯特丹）
你曾在「踩石」工作了三年
You'd been working at Treadstone for three years,
你当时的掩护身份是什么？
and your cover at the time was what?
巴黎的一名美国学生
That I was an American student in Paris.
你在巴黎为「踩石」所做的工作具体包括什么？
And what exactly did your job with Treadstone in Paris consist of?
我有两项职责 一是协调后勤行动
I had two responsibilities. One was to coordinate logistical operations.
二是监视探员们的健康
The other was to monitor the health of the agents.
- 健康？什么意思？- 精神健康
- Health, meaning what? - Their mental health.
- 因为他们所经历的事情 他们很容易出现各种问题 - 哪种问题？
- Because of what they had been through, they were prone to a variety of problems. - What kind?
沮丧 愤怒 强制行为
Depression, anger, compulsive behaviors.
他们有身体上的症状 头疼 怕光
They had physical symptoms. Headaches, sensitivity to light.
- 失忆症？- 伯恩之前？没有
- Amnesia? - Before Bourne? No.
飞机准备好了 车子正在等您
The plane's ready. There's a car waiting for you.
- 祝你们好运 - 不 你是他在当地的联络人
- Good luck. - No. you were his local contact.
康克林死的那晚你和他在一起 你要和我们一起走
You were with him the night Conklin died. you're coming with us.
兰利方面从那不勒斯取得了一段影像 正在上传中
Langley pulled an image out of Naples. It's uploading right now.
传过来了
It's coming in now.
- 我需要获准 - 显然 他并没有躲起来
- I need clearance. - He's not hiding, that's for sure.
- 为什么是那不勒斯？为什么是这个时候？- 可能是巧合
- Why Naples? Why now? - Could be random.
- 也许他正在逃跑 - 用他自己的护照？
- Maybe he's running. - On his own passport?
- 他到底在干什么？- 他在犯第一个错误
- What is he actually doing? - He's making his first mistake.
不是错误
It's not a mistake.
他们不会犯错 他们不会随意做事
They don't make mistakes. They don't do random.
总有一个目的 一个目标
There's always an objective. Always a target.
目的和目标应该是从我们这里发出的 那现在是谁在给他发号施令？
The objective and targets always came from us. Who's giving them to him now?
惊弓之鸟？
Scary version?
是的
He is.
（德国 慕尼黑）
- 子弹已经被我拿掉了 - 怪不得感觉轻了
- I emptied it. - It felt a little light.
放下枪
Put it down.
- 前面 - 对不起 老习惯了
- Front. - Sorry. Old habits.
用你的牙 啊
Use your teeth. Ah.
据说你失去记忆了
Word in the etherwas you'd lost your memory.
你该搬家的
You still should've moved.
- 你想要什么？- 康克林
- What do you want? - Conklin.
他死了
He's dead.
- 在巴黎被枪杀了 就在你出走的那天晚上死的 - 那现在谁负责「踩石」？
- Shot dead in Paris. Dead the night you walked out. - So who's running "Treadstone" now?
没人 关门大吉了
Nobody. They shut it down.
这些都已经过去了 我们是最后的两个
It's over. We're the last two.
如果是这样 那他们为什么还在追捕我？
If it's over, then Why are they still after me?
- 我不知道 - 听说过帕梅拉·兰蒂这个名字么？
- I don't know. - Ever heard the name Pamela Landy?
- 没听说过 - 帕梅拉·兰蒂和柏林 柏林发生了什么？
- I don't know who that is. - Pamela Landy and Berlin. What's going on in Berlin?
我不知道
I don't know.
我没必要撒谎
Why would I lie?
我以为你是来杀我的
I thought you were here to kill me.
- 你做了什么？- 对不起
- What'd you do? - I'm sorry.
你叫人来了？
Did you call it in?
站起来 过来
Get up. Come on.
- 你的车停在前面？- 钥匙在我上衣口袋里
- you have a car out front? - The keys are in my coat pocket.
- 但是我们应该… - 什么？
- But we should… - What?
从后面出去 我还有一辆车
Go out the back. I have another car.
我找帕梅拉·兰蒂
Pamela Landy.
- 没有这个人 先生 - 谢谢
- Nein, mein Herr. - Danke.
我想找帕梅拉·兰蒂
Pamela Landy.
没有这个人
Nein.
请问有没有一位帕梅拉·兰蒂
Pamela Landy, bitte.
有
Ja.
- 请接帕梅拉·兰蒂 - 请稍等
- Pamela Landy, please. - One moment, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想打电话给一位客人 帕梅拉·兰蒂
I wanted to call a guest. Pamela Landy.
请稍等片刻
Just one second, please.
喂？
Hello?
- 对不起 先生 现在对方电话占线 - 那过会儿再打吧 谢谢
- I'm sorry, sir. The phone's busy right now. - Just try later. Thank you.
好的 我们来看一下时间线 伯恩的目标是什么？
Okay. Let's take a look at the timeline. What's Bourne's objective?
现在我要把它分成几块
Now, I wanna break this out in boxes.
检查从那不勒斯往外发出的 所有航班和火车 还有警察报告 这是第一块
Naples outbound. Check everything. Flights, trains, police reports. That's box one.
- 泰迪 这块归你 - 明白
- Teddy, that's yours. - Got it.
第二块 把它称为「重要联系」
Box number two. Call it "prior connections."
重新看一遍伯恩的所有「踩石」材料 每个细节
I want to rerun al I Bourne's T readstone material. Every footstep.
基姆 第三块 我要你确定他的行动工具
Kim, box three. I want to identIf y his method ofitravel.
和当地警察保持联系 我们要找到某辆车 违章停车罚单什么的
Stay on the local cops. We need a vehicle, a parking ticket, something.
兰利方面为我们提供了卫星成像系统 让我们找个目标出来
Langley's offered to upload any satellite imaging we need, so let's find a target for them.
丹尼 第四块 另外派些人手 重新检查一下我们丢失奈斯基文件的现场
Danny, box four. I need fresh eyes. Review the buy where we lost the Neski files.
把我们对伯恩行踪的掌握标在时间线上 仔细检查 看看会有什么发现
Timeline it with what we know about Bourne's movements. Turn it upside down and see what we find.
加油干 伙计们！
Come on, guys.
这个家伙这么多年都生活在我们的完全掌控之下 我们应该能抢在他前头的
We ran this guy's life with total control for all those years. We should be a step ahead of him.
想要回家吗？找到杰森·伯恩吧！
You wanna go home? Find Jason Bourne.
- 帕梅拉·兰蒂 - 我是杰森·伯恩
- Pamela Landy. - This is Jason Bourne.
- 伯恩？- 是伯恩 我们需要90秒钟才能确定他的位置
- Bourne? - It's Bourne. We need 90 seconds to triangulate his position.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
现在是你负责「踩石」吗？
Are you running Treadstone?
「踩石」两年前就关闭了 你知道的
Treadstone was closed down two years ago. you know that.
那现在是谁在计划任务？
Then who's planning the missions now?
没有任务 已经结束了
There are no missions. It's over.
- 那你们找我干什么？- 柏林
- Then what do you want with me? - Berlin.
你忘了在柏林发生过什么吗？
Have you forgotten what happened in Berlin?
你杀死了两个人 伯恩 你杀死了两个人 伯恩
You killed two people, Bourne. you killed two people, Bourne.
你杀死了两个人 伯恩
You killed two people, Bourne.
奈斯基…弗拉迪米尔·奈斯基… 弗拉迪米尔·奈斯基…
Neski… Vladimir Neski… Vladimir Neski…
伯恩？
Bourne?
我要过来
I wanna come in.
- 好啊 你想怎么过来？- 还要35秒
- Okay. How do you wanna do it? - We need 35 seconds.
- 我要一个我认识的人带我过来 - 谁？
- I need someone I know to bring me in. - Who?
在巴黎有个女孩 她也参与了这个项目
There was a girl in Paris. She was part of the program.
她是负责后勤的 亚历山大街 30分钟后 世界钟下见
She used to handle logistics. Alexander Strasse, 30 minutes, under the World Clock.
让她一个人去 把你的手机给她
Send her alone. Give her your phone.
要是我找不到她呢？
What If I can't find her?
很简单 她就站在你旁边
It's easy. She's standing right next to you.
- 地区太多了… - 地形非常简单
- There's just so many areas… - It's a very simple lay out.
拿二区的地图来 摊开
Get the second quadrant. Pull it out.
在哪儿？请把二区的地图拿来 摊开
Where is it? Get the second quadrant, please. Pull it all the way up.
大钟就在这儿… 妈的 她的位置就在正中间
Clock is right here… Shit, he's put her in the middle of everything.
没法保护她的安全 在这里没办法掩护她
This is a security nightmare. There is no way we are going to get her covered…
给柏林警察局打电话 我们需要狙击手 国防部 有什么都调过来
Call a Mayday into Berlin station. We need snipers, D.O.D., whatever they've got.
不要狙击手 狙击手会把他吓跑的 我需要答案
No snipers. you put snipers on the roof and it'll scare him off, and I need answers.
- 你难道真的相信他要过来吗？- 他知道关于奈斯基的案子
- you can't really believe he wants to come in. - He knows something about the Neski case.
- 我不会错过这次找出真相的机会的 - 别傻了 这次我们离他只有一步之遥了
- I'm not gonna pass up this chance to find out what it is. - Don't be a fool. Not when we're this close.
我们是在讨论怎样保护妮基 还是怎样干掉伯恩？
Are we talking about protecting Nicky or killing Bourne?
- 我们在讨论怎样干掉伯恩 - 我们在讨论下一具尸体 可能是妮基 总会有人死的
- We're talking about killing Bourne. - We're talking about the next dead body. It might be Nicky. It will be someone.
你没在听我说 如果伯恩死了 我什么都得不到
You're not hearing me. Bourne dead gives me nothing.
我能私下和你谈谈么？
Can I talk to you privately?
- 什么？- 我知道你的感受
- What? - I know how you're feeling.
你在柏林牺牲了两个人 你希望他们死得其所
You lost two men in Berlin and you want it to mean something.
但是伯恩给你的东西不可能让他们死而复生
But nothing Bourne gives you will bring your men back.
那些文件的内容不能弥补他们的死 你必须想开点
Nothing in those files makes their sacrifice worthwhile. you have to let go.
我们是专业人士 如果一次行动失败了 就得了结它
We're professionals. When an operation goes bad, we tie it off.
如果你还有什么没有告诉我的话 我希望你在我把那个女孩派出去之前告诉我 你明白么？
If there's something you're not telling me, I want it now before I send that girl out there. Do you understand?
你好像是在纸上谈兵
You talk about this stuff like you read it in a book.
您想怎么办？
What do you want to do?
让狙击手就位
Put the snipers in place.
万一情况有变 我们就干掉他
If things go bad, we take him out.
明白
You got it.
总部 这里是一队 过来了一群人
Hub, this is Survey One. We have a crowd moving in.
- 好像是什么示威游行 - 对不起 我只能拉这么近了
- It's some sort of protest march. - I'm sorry. This is as close as I can get.
- 二队 你们能靠近些么？- 库尔特 保证南端的安全
- Survey Two, can you get in any closer? - Kurt, make sure the south end is covered.
收到 是 收到
Roger. Affirmative. Copythat.
- 喂？- 有辆电车正朝你开过来 上车
- Hello. - There's a tram coming towards you. Get on it.
- 她正向电车移动 - 车开往哪儿？
- She's moving to the tram. - Where's it going?
电车开往亚历山大广场车站
The tram is going to Alexanderplatz Station.
五队 我看不见他 我看不见他
Survey Five, I can't see him. I don't see him.
总部 这里是二队 她要上电车了
Hub, this is Survey Two, she's getting on a tram.
- 她要上电车了 - 放大电车
- She's getti ng on the tram. - Zoom in on the tram.
- 伯恩在电车上 - 我认为他不在电车上
- Bourne's on the tram. - I don't think he's on the tram.
他在电车上
He's on the tram.
派人进去跟着 让他们保持距离
Send them in to follow. Tell them to keep their distance.
好的 德尔塔 我们走 上车
Okay, Delta, let's go. Get on it.
我们走
Come on. Let's go.
- 让她快一点 - 南边什么都没有
- Tell herto hurry. - There's nothing on the south side.
亚历山大广场车站 25秒钟后到达
Alexanderplatz Station, 25 seconds.
这里是3队 这儿有很多示威人群 我们没办法掩护
This is Survey Three. There's a lot of protesters here. There's no way we can cover out there.
- 把她带出来 - 快！德尔塔 快！立即行动！
- Get her out of there. - Go! Delta, move! Now!
- 她不在这儿 她走了 - 该死！
- She's not here. She's gone. - Goddamn it!
- 他们没在电车上 - 他是一个人！
- They are not on the tram. - He's one guy!
- 杰森 请不要伤害我 - 我曾经说过什么？
- Jason, please don't hurt me. - What were my words?
我说过别来惹我 别把我搅进去
I said leave me alone, leave me out of it.
我是这么做的 我发誓 杰森 我告诉过他们我相信你
I did. I swear. Jason, I told them that I believed you.
我来问你几个简单的问题
I'm gonna ask you some some simple questions.
你要老实交待 否则我发誓一定杀了你
You're gonna answer me honestly, or I swear to God I'm gonna kill you.
- 德尔塔 快向我汇报情况 - 他们正在找！他们正在找！
- Delta, give me something. - They're on it! They're on it!
帕梅拉·兰蒂是谁？
Who's Pamela Landy?
- 她是一个特别行动组的负责人 - 现在是不是她在负责「踩石」？
- She's a task force chief. - Is she running "Treadstone"?
- 不 她是个副手 - 她为什么要杀我？
- No, she's the deputy director. - Why is she trying to kill me?
上个星期 她的手下跟一个线人进行一桩交易
Last week an agency field officer tried to make a buy off one of her opps.
线人好像原本打算出卖什么情报 但是让你捷足先登了
He was trying to sell out a mole or something and you got to him before we did.
- 我杀了他？- 你留下了指纹
- I killed him? - you left a print.
他们通过部分指纹查到了「踩石」 然后查到是你
There were partial prints that trace back to Treadstone. They know it was you.
- 荒谬 - 你为什么要这样做？为什么现在又回来？
- That is insane. - Why are you doing this? Why come back now?
- 兰蒂会找到… - 住口 住口
- Landy will find… - Stop. Stop.
上个星期 我在4000英里外的印度 看着玛丽死去
Last week I was 4, 000 miles away in India, watching Marie die.
他们是来杀我的 却要了她的命
They came for me, and they killed her instead.
现在结束了
This ends now.
找到她！
Find her.
你们想要我干什么？你们为什么要陷害我？
What do you people want with me? Why are you trying to frame me?
- 求你了 我来这只是因为巴黎的事儿 是艾博特把我们拉来的… - 艾博特？谁是艾博特？
- Please! I'm only here because of Paris. Abbott dragged us… - Abbott? Who's Abbott?
康克林的老板 是他…他关掉了「踩石」
Conklin's boss. He-He shut down Treadstone.
- 他现在在柏林吗？- 是的
- Is he here in Berlin? - Yes.
他负责「踩石」？
Did he run "Treadstone"?
- 他负责「踩石」？- 是的 康克林是他的下属
- Did he run "Treadstone"? - Yes. Conklin reported to him.
求你 求你了 我发誓…
Please. Please, I swear…
- 兰蒂要买的是什么东西？什么样的情报？- 康克林…有关康克林的
- What was Landy buying? What kind of files? - Conklin… Stuff on Conklin.
好像和一个俄国政客有关
It was something to do with a Russian politician.
- 奈斯基 - 什…什么？你说什么？
- Neski. - Wh-What? What are you talking about?
训练结束…训练结束… 训练结束…
Training is over… Training is over… Training is over…
我…我什么时候来过柏林？
When… When was I here in Berlin?
- 你在说什么？- 我曾经在这儿为「踩石」执行过一次任务
- What are you talking about? - For Treadstone. You know my file. I did a job here.
- 什么时候？- 不 你以前从没在柏林执行过任务
- When? - No, you never worked in Berlin before.
我的第一次任务 在柏林 你知道我的档案的
my first job. In Berlin. I did a job here. You know my file.
- 你从没在柏林执行过任务 - 我的第一次任务！
- you've never worked Berlin before. - my first job!
- 不 你的第一次任务是在日内瓦 - 你们这帮混蛋
- No, your first assignment was Geneva. - you fucking people!
- 我发誓！我发誓！- 我知道我来过这里 妮基！
- I swear! I swear! - I know I was here, Nicky!
- 你的档案里没有！- 我知道我来过这儿！
- It's not in your file! - I know I was here!
没有 我发誓…哦 求你了！
No, Iswear… Oh, please!
帕姆 你看 这是亚历山大广场
Pam, I want to show you something. It's Alexanderplatz.
一共三层 15条隧道 向外辐射到半径5个街区的范围内
We got three levels, we got 15 tunnels. They're all converging in a five-block radius.
那里 拉夫茨舒尔兹地堡 是一个旧的战时避难所
Over here, Luftschulzbunker. That was an old war shelter.
- 外面有多少人？- 两个正从后面楼梯下来 其余的成扇形搜索
- How many men are out there? - Two coming down the back stairs. The rest, they're fanned out for a search.
- 我们这的安全状况如何？- 哪里？「这里」？地面？
- What's our security situation here? - Where, "here"? The ground?
- 这里 就这栋楼 - 检查所有一切 楼梯、走廊和其它所有地方
- Here here. In the building. - Check everything, and recheck all the stairwells, hallways, everything.
好的
It's done.
好吧 索性公开吧 把他的照片交给柏林警方
Okay, let's go public. Release his photo to the Berlin police.
- 还要查一下他在印度的女友 - 我马上去办
- And check out his story about the girlfriend in India too. - I'm on it.
你麻烦大了 帕梅拉 而且你没法摆平
You're in a big puddle of shit, Pamela, and you don't have the shoes for it.
- 他说他不知道任何有关柏林的事情 - 他知道妮基戴着窃听器
- He said he didn't know anything about Berlin. - He knew that Nicky was wearing a wire.
- 你难道不觉得他是故意那么说的吗？- 听起来他不像是个被我控制的人
- Don't you think that was for our benefit? - He didn't sound like a man in control to me.
我们知道他来过柏林
We know he was in Berlin.
他的脑子坏了！是我们搞坏的 而且现在…
His mind is broken. We broke it. And now…
现在怎么样？干掉他？自从我们来这里以后你一直急着想要干掉他
What now? Terminate him? you've been pushing that agenda ever since we got here.
- 他还说你负责「踩石」 我们也应该相信这个么？- 我确信伯恩知道些什么
- He also said you were running Treadstone. Should we believe that too? - I'm convinced Bourne knows something.
他知道你在找他
He knows that you're after him,
而且他知道自我保护 你也应该知道
and in the interest of self-preservation you might start with that.
查一下那些照片 他们走了么？
Check on those photos. Have they gone out?
我有些东西给你看
I need to show you something.
我这块的工作已经做完了 但是在向兰蒂汇报之前 我想先给您看看
All right, I finished my box work, but I wanted to show you before I showed Landy.
昨晚我又来这儿看了一下…
Came down here last night…
因为我觉得这里有问题
because none of this is making any sense.
我同意你的看法…康克林是个疯子 但如果说他是叛徒
I'm with you… Conklin was a nut. But a traitor?
- 我不敢苟同 - 你发现什么了 丹尼？
- I just can't get there. - What do you have, Danny?
好吧 在这里放上炸药 就会摧毁大厦的电力系统
All right, you put a four-gam Kel on here, it's gonna take out power to the building.
你知道这点
You know that.
这儿有两个爆炸装置 本该同时引爆的 而这边这个并没有爆炸
There were two charges that were supposed to go off simultaneously. The second one, over here, didn't go off.
首先 这条线没用 这是上面那个断路器的副线
Now, first of all, this is nothing. It's a sub-line for the breaker above.
其次 为什么要在这儿放上第二个爆炸装置？
And second, Why put the charge all the way down here?
如果你有本事进来安放炸弹 你应该知道这个爆炸装置是没必要的
If you're good enough to get in here and handle the gear, you're good enough to know you don't need this.
伯恩肯定知道
Bourne would know.
- 是故意弄成这样的？- 看起来像是
- It was staged? - Is it a slam dunk? No.
要是有人想通过诬陷康克林和伯恩 来掩盖自己的罪行呢？
But what If somebody were trying to cover their tracks by blaming Conklin and Bourne?
要是伯恩根本和这件事没有关系呢？
What If Bourne didn't have anything to do with this?
- 再演示一遍 - 好的
- Show me again. - All right.
好的 你把…
Well, you put…
靠边停车 他要出来了
Pull over. He's getting out.
士兵 这次不是训练 清楚吗？
This is not a drill, soldier. We clear on that?
这次可是来真的 行动吧
This is a live project, and you're a go.
我们在另一头会合
I 'll see you on the other side.
- 晚上好 先生 需要帮忙吗？- 我想要个房间过夜
- Good evening, sir. How can I help you? - I want to get a room for the night.
- 您预订了吗？- 没有
- Do you have a reservation? - No.
实际上 我想住645房间 我以前在那住过
Actually, is room 645 available? I've stayed there before.
很抱歉 先生 那个房间已经有人了 644怎么样？
I'm sorry, sir. That room is occupied. How about room 644?
就在645对面
It's right across the hall.
先生？
Sir?
- 644？- 好的 谢谢
- 644? - That's fine. Thank you.
请出示您的护照 在这里签字
I just need your passport and signature right here, please.
祝您晚间愉快
Have a nice night.
是的
Ja.
柏林警察
Berlin Polizei.
- 在哪儿？- 布莱克酒店
- Where? - Brecker Hotel.
好的 我们马上就到 把车开过来！
Okay, we're there. Take the van!
- 布莱克酒店？多远？- 大概5、6分钟
- Brecker? How far? - About five or six minutes.
嗨
Hi!
嗨！
Hey!
祝贺你 士兵
Congratulations, soldier.
训练结束
Training is over.
警察！警察！
Polizei! Polizei!
行动！
Go!
黑色外套 可能是皮的 黑色T恤 黑色裤子
Black coat, possibly leather, dark T-shirt, dark pants.
警察要把所有客人集中 一个一个检查
The cops out there wanna corral all the guests together and check 'em out one by one.
很好
That will really work.
- 他到这里来干什么？- 也许只是想过夜
- What the hell's he doing here? - Maybe he just wanted to stay the night.
警察！
Polizei!
警察！警察！
Polizei! Polizei!
- 没抓到？- 是的 还没有
- They missed him? - Yeah, so far.
但是他们发现了妮基 她回维斯丁了 伯恩把她放了
But they found Nicky. She's back at the Westin. Bourne let her go.
- 把她放了？- 是的
- He let her go? - Yeah.
丹尼·索恩在哪儿？他应该过去给她录口供的
Where's Danny Zorn? He ought to head over there and debrief her.
伯恩为什么来这里？
Why did Bourne come here?
我们还不知道 兰蒂在上面的一个房间里
We don't know yet. Landy's upstairs in one of the rooms.
她说完事后给你打电话
She said she'd call you when she's done.
好的
Okay.
我想…我还是打车回酒店吧
I think I'll, uh… take a cab back to the hotel.
那么 他住的是大厅对面的那个房间
So, the room he checked into was across the hall.
嗯
Mmm.
他为什么到这来？
Why would he come in here?
- 你在想什么？- 我认得这房间 在哪张照片上见过
- What are you thinking? - I recognize this room from a photo.
这里曾经是一句尸体的粉笔轮廓线 弗拉迪米尔·奈斯基的尸体
There was a chalk outline right here around the body of Vladimir Neski.
他妻子就是在这杀了他？
This is where his wife killed him?
你还认为是他妻子杀了他？
Do you still think his wife killed him?
他可能是从这个窗子出去的
Guess he got out through this window.
我们刚从柏林警方得到消息
We just got word from the Berlin police.
他们发现了丹尼·索恩的尸体
They found Danny Zorn's body.
我要你们俩继续查伯恩 检查所有的东西
I want you two to stay on Bourne. Check everything that's out there.
打电话给艾博特 告诉他在酒店等我
Call Abbott. Tell him to wait for me in his hotel.
我马上去见他
I'm coming to see him.
- 喂 - 是我
- Da. - It's me.
他们开始查奈斯基的案子了
They're onto Neski.
- 这个电话不安全 - 没有伯恩他们什么都证明不了
- This is not a clean phone. - They can't prove anything without Bourne.
杀了伯恩 才能终止这次调查
Kill Bourne, and you kill this investigation.
沃德 恐怕我们该分道扬镳了
I'm afraid, Ward, the time has come for us to part company.
听着 尤里 你偷了中情局两千万美元 的种子基金才买到了那些油田的租用权
Listen, Yuri, you bought those oil leases with 20 million in stolen C.I.A. seed money.
- 你欠我的 - 你那份我已经给你了
- you owe me. - I gave you your cut.
我们都发了财
We both got rich.
我不欠你任何东西
I don't owe you anything.
这个计划还有拯救的希望 只要干掉伯恩 你听到没有？
The plan can still be salvaged. Just get Bourne. you hear me?
他还活着 干掉他
He's still out there. Now get him.
干掉杰森…
Get Jason…
我想我叫救命没有用吧 啊？
I don't suppose it would do me much good to cry for help, huh?
没什么用
Not much.
你杀了她
You killed her.
那是个失误
It was a mistake.
应该是你
It was supposed to be you.
有一些文件会把我和奈斯基的谋杀案联系到一起
There were files linking me to the Neski murder.
如果那些文件不见了 而他们怀疑是你
If the files disappeared and they suspected you,
那么他们永远都查不出真相
they'd be chasing a ghost for 10 years.
这么说我们碍了你们的事
So we got in the way.
因此你们杀了奈斯基？还有玛丽？
Is that Why Neski died? Is that Why you killed Marie?
是你杀了玛丽…
You killed Marie…
从你上她的车的那一刻起
the minute you climbed into her car.
从你进入她的生活的那一刻起 她就死了
The minute you entered her life, she was dead.
我说过让你们别来惹我！
I told you people to leave us alone.
我洗手不干了 躲到了半个地球以外
I fell off the grid. I was halfway around the world.
对你来说没有哪个地方是安全的
There's no place it won't catch up to you.
每个故事的结局都是这样
It's how every story ends.
杰森… 你注定是一个杀手
It's what you are, Jason… a killer.
永远都是
You always will be.
开枪吧 来吧！来吧！
Go ahead. Go on. Go on! Do it! Do it!
她不会让我这么做的
She wouldn't want me to.
这是你活下来的唯一理由
That's the only reason you're alive.
我是个爱国者 我为我的国家服务
I'm a patriot. I serve my country.
- 丹尼·索恩呢？他又是什么？- 他运气不好
- And DannyZorn? What was he? - Unlucky.
他是个附属牺牲品
Collateral damage.
那么 我们现在怎么办？
So, what do we do now?
我死而无憾
I'm not sorry.
不 不用了 他一到就给我打电话
No, no, no, forget it. Call me as soon as he's here.
不 那没用
No, that's nothing.
- 同步做得很好 - 这个人是谁？
- Good synch-up. - Who's this guy?
B站台
Plat form "B."
开枪吧 来吧！来吧！
Go ahead. Go on. Go on! Do it! Do it!
她不会让我这么做
She wouldn't want me to.
这是你活下来的唯一理由
That's the only reason you're alive.
兰利来了个电话
Got a call from Langley.
他们正在检查艾博特的档案
They're, uh, going through Abbott's records,
马歇尔想知道伯恩怎么样了
and Marshall wants to know what's going on with Bourne.
等等 泰迪 泰迪 这是谁？看这个家伙
Wait, Teddy. Teddy, who's this? Look at this guy.
他正要上车… 就在那儿！那儿！
He 's about to enter… Right there! There!
就在那儿 是伯恩
Ri ght through there. That's Bourne.
- 快下来！我们有发现了！- 我们发现伯恩了！快来看！
- Get down here! We got something! - We got a sighting! Check it out!
那边 我把图像传到大监视器上 等一下
There. I got it on the big monitor. Hold on.
就是这儿
Here it comes again.
- 好 好 慢一点 他刚进入画面 - 是那件衣服 是他！
- Whoa, whoa. Hold on. He's just entered frame. - It's the coat. That's him!
是哪趟火车？
What train is that?
- 开往莫斯科的 - 他去莫斯科干嘛？
- That's the train to Moscow. - Why the hell would he go to Moscow?
帮我接俄国内务部长
Get me the Russian interior ministry.
（俄罗斯 莫斯科）
你的电话关了 到底发生了什么事？
你说过我有一个月的假期
你告诉我杰森·伯恩死了
你能带我到这个地方么？
卢布？
美元
赶快行动 34号出租车… 刚离开火车站
喂
在这等着
那个美国人 是么？
你好
我找住在48号的女孩
奈斯基家的女孩？她不住这儿了
她从这座城市搬走了
我想是奥兰尼公寓 16号
我是特工！我是特工！
趴下 趴下！
趴下！
嗨 离我的车远点 笨蛋！
需要FSB支援 高速追击
安静 别出声好么？
我没有钱 也没有毒品 你想要什么？
坐下 坐下
坐在椅子上
我会说英语
I speak English.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
不会的
I won't hurt you.
你长大了
You're older.
比我想像的还要大
Older than I thought you'd be.
那照片
That picture.
对你来说很重要吧？
Does that mean a lot to you?
没什么 只是一张照片而已
It's nothing. It's just a picture.
不
No.
因为你不知道他们是怎么死的
It's 'cause you don't know how they died.
我知道
I do.
不 你不知道
No, you don't.
我想知道
I would want to know.
我想知道 我… 我妈妈没有杀死我爸爸
I would want to know that my … that my mother didn't kill my father,
她也不是自杀
that she didn't kill herself.
什么？
What?
你的父母并不是那么死的
It's not what happened to your parents.
是我杀的
I killed them.
那是我的工作
It was my job.
是我的第一次
It was my first time.
你父亲本该是一个人的
Your father was supposed to be alone.
但是你的母亲…
But then your mother…
突然出现
came out of nowhere,
我只好改变计划
and I had to change my plan.
事情因此而改变
It changes things,
变成你所知道的那样
that knowledge.
对吧？
Doesn't it?
当你的所爱从你身边被夺走时
When what you love gets taken from you,
你就想知道真相
you wanna know the truth.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 帕梅拉·兰蒂 - 我听说你还在找我
- Pamela Landy. - I hear you're still looking for me.
- 伯恩？- 你想要什么？
- Bourne? - What do you want?
我想谢谢你…
I wanted to thank you…
那盘磁带
for the tape.
我拿到了我要的东西 一切都结束了…结束了
We got what we needed. It's all tied off… It's over.
我想我该向你道歉
I guess I owe you an apology.
是官方的吗？
Is that official?
不 是私下的 你知道的
No. Off the record. you know how it is.
再见
Good-bye.
等等 等一下
Wait. Wait.
戴维·韦伯
David Webb.
那才是你的真名
That's your real name.
你出生在1971年4月15日 在密苏里州的涅克萨
You were born 4-15-71 in Nixa, Missouri.
为什么不过来谈谈呢
Why don't you come in and we'll talk about it.
伯恩？
Bourne?
你该休息一下了 帕姆 你看起来很累了
Get some rest, Pam. you look tired.